A Guide to the Papers of the English-Speaking Union Charlottesville Branch, 1982-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the English-Speaking Union Charlottesville Branch, 1982-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10599-f
This collection consists of (ca.) 320 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited by Mrs. Jan Daggett, Charlottesville, Va, 22901 in January 1999.
Biographical/Historical Information
International non-profit educational organization founded in 1920 to promote communication and understanding through the medium of the English language. The Charlottesville Branch was founded in 1952.
Scope and Content Information
The papers include minutes, by-laws, reports, correspondence, membership and officer rosters, notice of meetings, invitations, board meetings, brochures, programs, scholarship information, archival material, speakers' programs, and deposit agreements with Alderman Library.
The papers also include a file on a perfomance of a British Embassy Players benefit on behalf of Union's scholarship fund.
Contents List
- British Embassy Players Benefit, 1996-1997
- Correspondence, 1990-1996
- English Speaking The ESU News and Branch Officers' Bulletin, 1988-1994
- Invitations to Events, 1990-1998, n.d., 2 folders
- Membership Rosters, ca. 1992-1996
- Memoranda of Agreement with Alderman Library, including correspondence 1983-1996
- Minutes, 1993-1996
- Miscellaneous, ca. 1994-1997
- Officers, 1989-1992, n.d.
- Scholarship Committee, 1982-1990
- Thank You Letters from Scholarship Recipients, 1983-1987
- Poster re the British Embassy Players, 1996, Oversized folder. (Oversize P-16)